A Guide to Local History and Memorabilia
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
A Guide to Local History and Memorabilia 1887-1992
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1976-55f
100 pieces
Petersburg and Virginia State University have had a long relationship beggining in 1883. Over this period of time many conferences and programs about Petersburg have been held on the campus of Virginia State University. Additionally, many instructors and officers of the University have been involved in various aspects of the political, social, and economic life of Petersburg.
An artificial collection created by members of the library staff.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Biographical/Historical Information
An artificial collection created by members of the library staff.
Scope and Content Information
Programs, Pamphlets, and flyers of programs, and events are included in this manuscript group. A particular interest are broadsides and flyers announcing various meetings and events.
Contents List
- Local History and Memorabilia
  - Program: Joseph Jenkins Roberts Day 1947 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - Program: Joseph Jenkins Roberts 1986 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Program: Corner Stone Laying, Petersburg General Hospital 1951 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Peoples Memorial Cemetary Correspondence (copies) 1941-1944 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Peoples Memorial Cemetary Plat Map (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Program: First Baptist Church Celebrating 200 years 1974 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - The Little Chapel in Pocahontas (Deal) (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Program: The PIA Petersburg Improvement Association 1961 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Program: The PIA 1966 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Flyer: St. Stevens Church Building Fund 1906 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Education in Ettrick (copy) 1887 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Flyer: Events at YMCA Hall 1902 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Paper: Rodgers, Ernestine The Third Baptist Church 1987 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Paper: Henderson,William,Petersburg Confederate City (Box-folder 1:14)
  - Paper: Henderson,William, Civil War Petersburg 1982 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Event: William Dellwood, Chris Calkins, Edward Coles, Lucious Edwards, William Henderson, and James W. Smith (Box-folder 1:16)
  - James W. Smith The History and Legend of Pocahontas (3 copies) (Box-folder 1:17)
  - Marvin T. Broyhill The Appomattox Iron Works 1989 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - The Messenger of the Chesterfield Historical Society of Virginia 1982-1992 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - Peabody High School Golden Class Reunion 1984 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Annual Meeting of the 4th District Teachers Association 1947 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - The Petersburg Civic Association Yearbook (2 Copies) 1930-931 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - The 2nd Annual Fair of the Colored Agricultural and Industrial Association of Virginia 1887 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Petersburg, Virgina Visit by William Howard Taft 1909 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Brief History and Program of the 136th Anniversary of Gillfield Baptist Church William Henry Johnson (3 copies) (Box-folder 2:8)
  - Negro Business Directory 1933 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - Luther Porter Jackson A Short History of Gillfield Baptist Church 1937 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - The Church and The Negro The Bishop Payne School 1944 (Box-folder 2:11)
  - Founders and Jackson Day Dinner Sponsered by the Virginia Voters League 1959 (Box-folder 2:12)
  - The Negro Business Association 1937 (Box-folder 2:13)
  - The Installation of the Reverend Andrew Jackson White 1963 (Box-folder 2:14)
  - The Zion Herald News Volume 1 #1- Volume 8 # 4 (Volume 2:15)
  - Bass Fishing Day Florence S. Farley (Mayor) James D. McNeil (Mayor) 1986 (Box-folder 2:16)
  - Martin Luther King Program at Gillfield 1987 (Box-folder 2:17)